<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-04-01T19:21:18+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why another literary review?</title><link href="/general/2024/04/01/wherefore-art-thou.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why another literary review?" /><published>2024-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2024-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/general/2024/04/01/wherefore-art-thou</id><content type="html" xml:base="/general/2024/04/01/wherefore-art-thou.html"><![CDATA[<p>The easier way to answer a question is by beginning to unravel the question itself – pull the earth beaneath its feet and it may yield to its own demands. It is also a time-tested way to clarify the mind itself in the centifuge of circumlocution. One way to begin is by answering Eliot’s complaint, that most literary reviews fall into one or some of the errors that he enumerates. For example, a review may be too wide or too narrow in its material and scope, it may be too autocratic or too anarchic, editorially speaking, and so on. Chief among these flaws is catering to one man’s taste and that man’s alone. Another is a strict adherence to a’programme’. The way out of these extremities of virtue is by resorting to a <strong>Tendency</strong>.</p>

<p>What tendency does this review proclaim? A difficult question, more so in the diversity of the current literary scene. Yet, by virtue of this difficulty or otherwise, it is also one of those questions that can be answered retrospectively and need only be answered slantly at present. To declare a tendency, it is better to define the tendency of this tendency in forming itself. So let it suffice at the moment that <strong>The Monad</strong> will first gather its components from the literary world and only then appraise the results recursively. The submission guidelines for the first issue will shed more light on the matter. Sure, a few terms like quality, integrity, inventiveness, classicity etc can be thrown in but this really does not add much.</p>

<p>There are a few questions that loom over any effort of this sort. Inclusivity, for example. Any collection can either challenge the existing canon or feed it.</p>]]></content><author><name>coldsteelpen</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The easier way to answer a question is by beginning to unravel the question itself – pull the earth beaneath its feet and it may yield to its own demands. It is also a time-tested way to clarify the mind itself in the centifuge of circumlocution. One way to begin is by answering Eliot’s complaint, that most literary reviews fall into one or some of the errors that he enumerates. For example, a review may be too wide or too narrow in its material and scope, it may be too autocratic or too anarchic, editorially speaking, and so on. Chief among these flaws is catering to one man’s taste and that man’s alone. Another is a strict adherence to a’programme’. The way out of these extremities of virtue is by resorting to a Tendency.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PDF</title><link href="/reading/2024/03/01/pdfsample.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PDF" /><published>2024-03-01T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2024-03-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/reading/2024/03/01/pdfsample</id><content type="html" xml:base="/reading/2024/03/01/pdfsample.html"><![CDATA[<p>PDF
PDF</p>]]></content><author><name>coldsteelpen</name></author><category term="reading" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[PDF PDF]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Stone Angel</title><link href="/reading/2021/04/14/the-stone-angel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Stone Angel" /><published>2021-04-14T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2021-04-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/reading/2021/04/14/the-stone-angel</id><content type="html" xml:base="/reading/2021/04/14/the-stone-angel.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Stone Angel by Margaret Lawrence is a rare book both in its choice of protagonist and language. It is unifromly poetic with a rustic prairie charm peppered in. The range and depth of emotion can hardly be found in another novel. One can say, even Joyce and Woolf pale in front of this insightful treatment of old age and womanhood. So far, I have not been able to pick up reading pace because reading this book is like a slow walk through strange
Canadian woods and one has to stop and admire the tendrillous manifestations of lingusitic shoots.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/pxArtStoneAngel.png" alt="Clouds" height="400" /></p>

<p>The most touching moment in the first quarter of the book is when Hagar denies her brother’s request to don their mother’s shawl to comfort their dying brother. She has not seen her mother, she died birthing her, and cannot bring herself to put on the pretence of being her even though she loves her brother.</p>]]></content><author><name>coldsteelpen</name></author><category term="reading" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Stone Angel by Margaret Lawrence is a rare book both in its choice of protagonist and language. It is unifromly poetic with a rustic prairie charm peppered in. The range and depth of emotion can hardly be found in another novel. One can say, even Joyce and Woolf pale in front of this insightful treatment of old age and womanhood. So far, I have not been able to pick up reading pace because reading this book is like a slow walk through strange Canadian woods and one has to stop and admire the tendrillous manifestations of lingusitic shoots.]]></summary></entry></feed>